Alex Ennis

615-587-0886 · aedevelopes@gmail.com · <u>linkedin.com/in/ennistech/</u> · <u>github.com/aedevelopes</u>
400 Herron Drive #207, Nashville TN

DATA ANALYST

A multifaceted individual with seven years of experience analyzing and troubleshooting in the field; two of which were focused on automated robotic systems in pharmacy and lab settings. I enjoy manipulating and pulling trends from databases. I'm looking to transition into a field where I can use these skills to help the world make better decisions. When I'm not in front of a computer, you can find me on the disc golf course.

KEY COMPETENCIES

Python	Excel	Automated Systems
SQL	Tableau	IT Operations
C++	PowerBI	Info Management Systems

EXPERIENCE

Nashville Software School Data Analyst Apprentice

Jan 2022 - Apr 2023

Lead multiple Projects, extracting and sorting through data from multiple different sources. Created Visualizations and predicted outcomes for future years.

Accomplishments:

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Built and deployed dashboards using Tableau and PowerBI
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- · Gathered data through APIs and webscraping
- Performed geospatial analysis using geopandas and folium
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL and sglalchemy
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

Parata Systems Jan 2021 - Jan 2023

Field Support Engineer I&II

Worked with a team to cover a district that stretched over 700 miles, maintaining a 90% uptime of all machines and less than 24 hr downtime average fixrate. Ensured >90% customer satisfaction via surveys. Secured a promotion to level II within the first year.

Accomplishments:

- Performed analyses on SQL Server to manage and verify patient information.
- Calibrated machines using .XML and .Config editors
- Managed database network connections through Host Interface and AIM connections
- Ensured technical information was updated by reviewing manuals, service bulletins, and product reference material, updating them on Salesforce when needed
- Applied expertise and statistical analysis to find new solutions to problems; referring to schematics when needed
- Provided advanced-level technical support through the performance of on-site servicing, repair, and installation of complex pharmacy automation and robotics systems

Worked on the frontlines of the Covid-19 Epidemic by running extractions and PCR on patient samples. Worked the nightshift, cleaning up the remainder of the samples that the day shift wasnt able to get to. These leftovers sometimes reached up to >30 plates a night, each containing 94 patient samples.

Accomplishments:

- Logged specimens into Laboratory Information Management System (LIMS) ensuring accurate demographic and testing request entries
- Complied with all laboratory safety and quality procedures and requirements, including GCP and FDA requirements
- First night-shift technician to learn both methods of extraction, able to be shifted to wherever I was needed
- Used a plethora of liquid handling equipment to accurately test samples

April 2013 - Feb 2017

PROJECTS

SQL https://github.com/aedevelopes/lahman_baseball-Ennis SQL Project that cleans data of baseball statistics over many years.

Tableau https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/alex.ennis

Tableau project that showcases Starbucks locations and compares them to census data.

PowerBI https://drive.google.com/file/d/1qumcOmp0s-pZIZDtJsN-

kECtx9GManS5/view?usp=share_link

PowerBI dashboard that compares player stats in the NBA over several years.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School, Certificate

Data Analyst Certification

University of Tennessee

B.A in Neuroscience

Volstate Community College

A.S in Computer Science